Hamid Ghader

hamid.ghader@live.com linkedin.com/in/hghader

ABOUT

I am a software engineer with 15+ years of experience in delivering software systems for a wide range of business domains. I have worked as a software developer and a technical lead, involved in different stages of software development from inception to delivery.

I am a proficient coder in several programming languages. I am familiar with modern software architectures and concepts, including Microservices, Event Sourcing and CQRS, MVC, Reactive Programming, and Domain-driven design. I am particularly interested in design and development of Cloud-native distributed systems.

SKILLS

```
Languages: Go C# JavaScript/TypeScript Visual Basic

Databases: PostgreSQL SQL Server MongoDB Oracle Elasticsearch Redis

Messaging: Kafka NATS gRPC Protocol Buffers RESTful API JSON XML

Operations: AWS Kubernetes Docker CI/CD Git Terraform Prometheus Grafana

Web: ASP.NET (WebForms/MVC) HTML CSS Chrome Extensions Selenium WebDriver
```

EXPERIENCE

Aug 2019 - Present, Senior Software Engineer, Uswitch (London, UK)

- Main contributor of the Energy Savings Calculator. A highly concurrent service written
 in Go that makes millions of comparisons every day to help customers save money on
 their bills. Drives 15% of the company's energy comparison revenue.
- Contributed in migrating over 25 services between Kubernetes clusters with 100% availability in mind.
- Worked on the Customer Store. A central repository to store all customers data with an aim to simplify data analysis, GDPR processing, and cross-selling.

2018 - 2019, Software Engineer, Utility Warehouse (London, UK)

• As part of the Energy Team, delivered various microservices using Go, Kafka, Protocol Buffers, and gRPC for the new Smart Metering platform.

2014-2018, Technical Lead, Geeks Ltd (London, UK)

- Involved in full software development life-cycle of multiple projects. Interacted with PMs and BAs in UX design/wireframing process, project/sprint planning, providing estimations, and task delegation.
- In charge of technical direction of projects, making architectural and design decisions, providing technical support, and reporting to directors.

2010-2013, Senior Software Developer, Geeks Ltd (London, UK)

- Successfully delivered several bespoke client projects on time and on budget.
- Contributed to company's growth through knowledge sharing and training new developers.

2004-2009, Software Developer, Various companies (Tehran, Iran)

- Provided a software solution to Cutting Stock Problem (CSP) using Genetic Algorithms, used by aluminium door and window makers to minimise their cutting waste.
- Redeveloped legacy MS Access accounting and stock management systems using C# and SQL Server with a focus on improving user experience.

EDUCATION

MSc Information Systems Development

• 2010-2011, London Metropolitan University (London, UK)

BSc Applied Computer Software

• 2004-2007, Shamsipour Institute of Technology (Tehran, Iran)

Last update: March 2021

EOF